Adam Seewald, Curriculum Vitae

Most recent version: adamseewald.cc/cv, ₺

Webpage adamseewald.cc

Email adam.seewald@aya.yale.edu

Phone +1 (774) 333-2250

Environmental Robotics Lab

Zürcherstrasse 111 Address 8903 Birmensdorf ZH

Switzerland

I am currently a postdoc at the Environmental Robotics Lab, ETH Zürich

 My research focuses on robotics and computer science and involves autonomous robots in different environmental use cases

 My fields of research interest are aerial robotics, field robots, motion and path planning, and energy and environment-aware automation, among others (RAS classif. ♂)

Education

2018-2022 Ph.D., Engineering Science, University of Southern Denmark

Energy-aware coverage planning and scheduling for autonomous aerial robots, ✷

Advisor Prof. Ulrik Pagh Schultz

2016-2018 Master, Computer Science and Engineering, University of Verona, Italy

Thesis Evaluation of optimal trajectories for quadrotors with indirect methods in the presence of intermediate

constraints

Advisor Prof. Paolo Fiorini

2013-2016 Bachelor, Computer Science, University of Verona, Italy

Experience

2024-Postdoc, Environmental Robotics Lab, Dept. of Environmental Systems Science, ETH Zürich

Project Robot-assisted collection of eDNA for pest detection in precision agriculture, C (PI: Stefano

Mintchev)

Funding World Food System Center and Fenaco's research program on smart sustainable farming

Development of techniques (i.e., aerial-physical interaction, RGB-D perception, etc.) for the collection and analysis of environmental DNA samples for the detection of pests in precision agriculture.

2022-2024 Postdoc, GRAB Lab, Dept. of Mechanical Eng. and Materials Science, Yale University

Project Mobile ground-based and aerial robots for biodiversity surveying, ♂ (PI: Aaron M. Dollar)

Funding Yale University's discretionary research fund

Details Development of mobile robotic autonomy (i.e., navigation, control, and planning algorithms and

communication methodologies) for nature conservation and surveying efforts [c7, c6].

2018-2022 Ph.D. Researcher, Unmanned Aerial Systems Center, University of Southern Denmark

TeamPlay - Time, Energy, and security Analysis for Multi/Many-core heterogeneous PLAtforms, ♂

(PI: Ulrik Pagh Schultz)

Funding European Union's Horizon2020 program under grant agreement number 779882

Details Development of the aerial robotics use case [c4] (i.e., fixed-wing aerial robot for precision agriculture).

Development of an open-source motion planning/computing energy modeling library [j1, o1] utilized

by a network of collaborators including University of Amsterdam, University of Bristol, and INRIA.

Research

Peer-reviewed journal publication:

[j1] • Adam Seewald, Ulrik Pagh Schultz, Emad Ebeid, and Henrik Skov Midtiby, "Coarse-grained computation-oriented energy modeling for heterogeneous parallel embedded systems," in International Journal of Parallel Programming. 2021; vol. 49, no. 2, pp. 136–157. 10.1007/s10766-019-00645-y, □

Peer-reviewed conference publications (7):

- [c7] Adam Seewald, Cameron J. Lerch, Marvin Chancán, Aaron M. Dollar, and Ian Abraham, "Energy-aware ergodic search: Continuous exploration for multi-agent systems with battery constraints," to appear in IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA'24), p. 7. 🖒
- [c6] Adam Seewald, Marvin Chancán, Connor M. McCann, Seonghoon Noh, Omeed Fallahi, Hector Castillo, Ian Abraham, and Aaron M. Dollar, "RB5 Low-cost explorer: Implementing autonomous long-term exploration on low-cost robotic hardware," to appear in IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA'24), p. 7.
- [c5] Benjamin Rouxel, Christopher Brown, Emad Ebeid, Heiko Falk, Clemens Grelck, Jesper Holst, Shashank Jadhav, Yoann Marquer, Marcos Martinez Alejandro, Kris Nikov, Ali Sahafi, Ulrik Pagh Schultz, <u>Adam Seewald</u>, Vangelis Vassalos, Simon Wegener, and Olivier Zendra, "**The TeamPlay project: Analysing and optimising time, energy, and security for cyber-physical systems**," in Design, Automation and Test in Europe Conference (DATE'23), pp. 1–6. 10.23919/DATE56975.2023.10137198, ©
- [c4] Adam Seewald, Héctor García de Marina, Henrik Skov Midtiby, and Ulrik Pagh Schultz, "Energy-aware planning-scheduling for autonomous aerial robots," in IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS'22), pp. 2946–2953. 10.1109/IROS47612.2022.9981285, ♂
- [c3] Georgios Zamanakos, Adam Seewald, Henrik Skov Midtiby, and Ulrik Pagh Schultz, "Energy-aware design of vision-based autonomous tracking and landing of a UAV," in IEEE International Conference on Robotic Computing (IRC'20), pp. 294–297. 10.1109/IRC.2020.00054, ©
- [c2] Adam Seewald, Héctor García de Marina, Henrik Skov Midtiby, and Ulrik Pagh Schultz, "Mechanical and computational energy estimation of a fixed-wing drone," in IEEE International Conference on Robotic Computing (IRC'20), pp. 135–142. 10.1109/IRC.2020.00028, ♂
- [c1] Adam Seewald, Ulrik Pagh Schultz, Julius Roeder, Benjamin Rouxel, and Clemens Grelck, "Component-based computation-energy modeling for embedded systems," in ACM SIGPLAN International Conference on Systems, Programming, Languages, and Applications: Software for Humanity (SPLASH'19), pp. 5–6. 10.1145/33590 61.3362775, 🖒

Peer-reviewed workshop publications (2):

- [w2] Adam Seewald, "Beyond traditional energy planning: The weight of computations in planetary exploration," in IROS Workshop on Planetary Exploration Robots: Challenges and Opportunities (PlanRobo'20), p. 3. ETH Zürich. 10.3929/ethz-b-000450120, [2]
- [w1] Adam Seewald, Emad Ebeid, and Ulrik Pagh Schultz, "Dynamic energy modelling for SoC boards: Initial experiments," in Workshop on High-Level Programming for Heterogeneous and Hierarchical Parallel Systems (HLP-GPU'19), p. 4. 답

Others (2):

- [o2] Adam Seewald, "Energy-aware coverage planning and scheduling for autonomous aerial robots," Ph.D. thesis, p. 184. Syddansk Universitet. Det Tekniske Fakultet, 2021. 10.21996/7ka6-r457, ♂
- [o1] Adam Seewald, Ulrik Pagh Schultz, Emad Ebeid, and Henrik Skov Midtiby, "powprofiler computations energy modeling tool," v. 1.0.2, 2021. 10.5281/zenodo.5562457, ♂

Invited lectures

- Solving energy-aware ergodic search problems via interior point methods. Invited Speaker at the ICRA Tutorial on Ergodic Control, IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation. May 13, 2024.
- Energy-aware dynamic planning: Merging path planning and computations scheduling for the drone use-case. Invited Talk at the TeamPlay Final Workshop, (Virtual Event). May 27, 2021.
- Energy estimation and modeling for the drone use-case. Invited Talk at the TeamPlay Workshop, European Network on High-Performance Embedded Architecture and Compilation Conference. January 22, 2020.

Teaching and advising

Teaching at graduate and undergraduate levels (2):

tal science.

Fall 2022		You, Your Planet, and a Sustainable Future, Yale University
	Role	Teaching assistant (PI: Aaron M. Dollar)
	Details	Survey course on sustainable technologies for undergraduate students in engineering and environmen-

Spring 2019, '20 Optimization and Control, University of Southern Denmark

Role Teaching assistant (PI: Agus Hasan)

Details Elective course on numerical optimization, methods and solvers, for master's students in robot systems

Advising of graduate and undergraduate students (2):

- Omeed Fallahi, undergraduate student in computer science, Yale University, 2022–2023
- Magnus O. C. Liisberg, master's student in robot systems, University of Southern Denmark, 2018–2019

Professional and outreach activities

- Member, Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE), 2019–
- Member, Association for Computing Machinery (ACM), 2019–
- Organizer of the Time, Energy, and Security Analysis for Multi/Many-core Heterogeneous Platforms Final Workshop (TeamPlay'21)
- Program Committee member, IEEE International Conference on Robotic Computing (IRC'23,'22,'21), ♂
- Reviewer, IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters (RA-L), □
- Reviewer, IEEE International Conference on Soft Robotics (RoboSoft'24), &
- Reviewer, IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA'24), □
- Reviewer, IEEE International Conference on Automation Science and Engineering (CASE'23), &
- Reviewer, IEEE International Conference on Robot and Human Interactive Communication (Ro-man'22)
- Reviewer, IEEE International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems (ICUAS'22), &
- Reviewer, International Workshop on Robotics Software Engineering (RoSE'22), ☑
- Reviewer, IEEE International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems (ICUAS'21)
- Reviewer, IEEE International Conference on Control, Automation, Robotics and Vision (ICARCV'20)

References

Prof. Aaron M. Dollar, ♂
Department of Mechanical Engineering and Materials Science
Yale University
aaron.dollar@yale.edu

Prof. Ulrik Pagh Schultz, ♂ SDU UAS Center Mærsk Mc-Kinney Møller Institute University of Southern Denmark ups@mmmi.sdu.dk Prof. Agus Hasan, ♂
Department of Natural Sciences
Norwegian University of Science
and Technology
agus.hasan@ntnu.no

Last updated: April 16, 2024